Sabbath is a practice from the way of Jesus by which we cultivate a spirit of restfulness
in all of our lives. It's a rhythm that God the Creator built into the fabric of the human body
and creation itself. Every seventh day, we stop, rest, delight, and worship.
Sabbath is for all of us in every stage of life and in every season.
Through Sabbath, we say yes to the easy yoke of Jesus and find rest for our souls.
Well, good morning. Hope you all are doing well. It's so good to see you. If I haven't
had the privilege of meeting you yet, my name is Ryan and I am one of the pastors here.
And I'm just glad that you're able to join us. We are launching back into this series that we've
been in for three years. How many of you were here when we kicked off the Practicing the Way series?
Pretty good number of you. That's awesome. So it's a three-year kind of nine-part series on
practice-based discipleship, and we've broken them up into kind of four-week mini-series on different
spiritual practices from the life and teaching of Jesus. And these practices are aimed at helping us
grow into the image of Jesus. The whole purpose of building these rhythms into our life is that the
Holy Spirit would use them to change us into a people of Christ-like love. And oftentimes in church,
one of the things this series targets is that we have this way of elevating insight,
overchange. That we like the idea of learning new information about God, and we can kind of check
the box on the spiritual thing. Like, I learn more information. I know more about God. But this
series is really aimed at us actually putting the teachings and the example of Jesus into practice.
They serve not only as a formational purpose. It's not just about forming us into Jesus, but it's also a
counter-formation one. They don't only help us in the Spirit's work of conforming us into the image of Jesus,
also help us fight against the enemy's work of conforming us into the image of this world.
They are practical habits where we make our entire selves available to the transforming work of the
Spirit. It's really this delicate balance that we kind of present ourselves to God, and He does the
work in us. There's this really confusing Scripture in the New Testament that it says,
work out your salvation with fear and trembling, which doesn't sound anything like the Protestant
gospel, right? For by grace you have been saved through faith, it is not by works. And then
we hear, work out your salvation with fear and trembling, but the next verse says that it is
actually God that does the work in you. So there's this partnership that we have with God, and the
practices are about us showing up and making space for Him to transform us. And so far we've covered
prayer, fasting, generosity, solitude, community, and service. And if you haven't, if you weren't here for
any of those, you want to catch up on those, you can go back and find them online. And we'd love for you
to do that. And then moving forward, we have three practices left that are Sabbath, Scripture, and
witness. And today, as you noticed from the video, we will be looking at one of the most challenging,
counter-cultural, misunderstood, and ignored practices from the life and teachings of Jesus.
Sabbath. Buckle up. Let's pray. Father, we are grateful for an opportunity to gather together
with other brothers and sisters in Christ to cast aside the worries and anxieties of this world and
to set our minds' attention on You. For those in the room that aren't yet followers of You, that are
just curious and interested in what You have to say, I pray that today would be an enlightening and
eye-opening experience for them to understand what You came to bring with the gospel of the kingdom of
God, that they might receive it for the first time. And for those of us who have already received it,
God, just wipe away all of our preconceived notions that do not contribute to the truth of Your
Scriptures and conform us more into Your image, not only for our good, but for the good of our neighbors
and for Your glory. It's in Jesus' name I pray. Amen.
We're going to start in Genesis 2 here in just a minute. So if you want to turn there, it shouldn't
be hard to find. It's like page two of the Bible. We'll start there. There are notes on the back of
the bulletin. So if you are a person that likes to follow along and fill in, please feel free to do that.
As I was preparing for this first message on Sabbath, I was just thinking about the cultural realities of our
day. Me as a father of a two-year-old and just both me and my wife working full-time jobs and thinking about
what is this, what is the challenge of experiencing Sabbath? And I don't know about you, but I feel like we live in a
fast-paced, individualistic, and consumeristic society. Does that feel right to the rest of us?
We're constantly bombarded with endless opportunities to participate in content to consume and products that
are being marketed to us. And for many of us, this can lead to a conscious or unconscious feeling of what
the cultural commentators have so eloquently called FOMO. Anybody have it? Anybody had it before?
Fear of missing out. We don't want to miss out on the best events, the best entertainment, or the best
products. So we fill our calendars with endless activities. Our downtime with either endless scrolling
or binging, or if you're really down the rabbit hole, you scroll while you binge.
And our credit cards are filled with increasing levels of debt, all so that we or our kids might not
miss out on the thing that we think will add value to their lives.
This is a good desire in us. We want to add value to our lives, but my argument this morning is that we
might actually be chasing the wrong solution for a right desire. I think if we really stopped to think
about this pattern of our lives, we'd probably admit that in some ways, the full calendars, the lack of
downtime, the increasing debt, isn't adding as much value as we thought it would. And it might actually be
leaving us feeling pretty worn down and tired. Anybody else worn down and tired this morning from full
calendars and busy schedules? And so this morning, what I want to do, and really for the next four weeks,
is I want to cast a compelling vision that maybe, just maybe, the things that we're chasing after in
our fear of missing out is actually causing us to miss out on the thing we actually need the most,
the thing that might bring us everlasting value to our lives, the thing that we were created for,
but have lost sight of. And that's what the Bible would talk about as Sabbath, or this period of time
time to stop the productivity and the work and the restlessness, and just to take a break and to rest
in the presence of God. Now, I know what you might be thinking. Sabbath, really? Isn't this an outdated
Old Testament command that doesn't apply to us anymore? Wasn't Jesus pretty harsh towards the Pharisees'
practice of the Sabbath? So why should we consider such a thing in the New Testament? Well, again,
over the next four weeks, we hope to cast a compelling vision that Sabbath isn't intended to be this legalistic
ritual, but it's a weekly appointed time. It's an invitation from God to stop producing, to rest, to delight in
God's creation, and to worship Him, who invites you to just take a break and rest in His presence. It isn't a
secluded religious ritual for the nation of Israel during a small period of human history. It actually starts on page
one of the Bible. It's built into the fabric of creation. It's developed throughout the Old Testament.
It's critiqued and clarified in the New Testament, and I would argue that it's actually fulfilled on the
final page of Scripture. I heard Tim Mackey say that Sabbath is one of the central threads of all of
Scripture. But we often don't see it because we've been trained with this, oh, it's not for me, or Jesus
critiqued it. And so I really want to just kind of wipe all of that away and take a fresh look at the
Scriptures and see this invitation that I think God might be giving to us. Now, before we hop into the
weeds, I do want to give just a knowledge up front, the difficulty that might come with receiving an
invitation like this. Many of us have never been taught on it or even considered it before.
Others of us might never be able to Sabbath without the support of our community or a change in our
economic status. This is a hard invitation to receive in our current cultural moment, 24 hours a
week of not working. For some of us, we wouldn't be able to pay our bills if that was the reality. So I
just want to acknowledge that tension up front and say later in the message, I will give some practical
tips for how we might work towards receiving this invitation from God. It might take us a long time,
but I don't think that that means we shouldn't consider it. I myself have been working towards
it for years and am by no means perfect at it. But if you would acknowledge that the trajectory of
your current situation, your current scheduling, your current life is leaving you tired and worn out
and feeling like your soul desperately needs rest, then maybe just maybe we should consider what it
would look like working towards something like this. I love the quote from A.J. Swobody. He says,
the key is not that we do Sabbath perfectly. The key is that we try. This is pastoral invitation.
So with all that background in mind, let's hop into Genesis 2. And on your notes, you'll see that I
want the first argument I want to make is that Sabbath is actually a rhythm woven into creation.
From Genesis chapter 2, starting in verse 1, this is kind of the crescendo, the climax of
our first explanation of the creation account. If you, maybe you know this, maybe you don't, we actually
have two accounts of the creation happening. And so this is kind of the climax of the first account
of creation in Genesis chapter 2, starting in verse 1. It says, we'll go 131. God saw all that he had
made and it was very good. And there was evening and morning on the sixth day. Thus, the heavens and the
earth were complete in all their vast array. By the seventh day, God had finished the work that he had
been doing. So on the seventh day, he rested from all of his work. Then God blessed the seventh day
and made it holy because on it, he rested from all of the work of creating that he had done.
So the first thing I just, I want us to point out here is that God chooses to finish his work.
He chooses to stop producing. He chooses to rest. God Sabbath. And I think this immediately eliminates
the tight chest of those type A's in the room that are like, yeah, you don't know. I'm so important.
I have so many things that I have to accomplish. If I don't do, God rest it. And if God can rest,
then that means you're not too important to rest. Some of the rabbis even argue that part of being an
image bearer is knowing when to stop. That God models for us in his image that he knows when to stop.
Like an excellent painter who knows when the last brushstroke has gone onto the canvas. You could
ruin a painting by doing too much. God knows when to stop. And some rabbis would argue that that's part
of our image bearer, that we have to know when to say enough. And oftentimes, because there's endless
money to be made, endless opportunities to chase in our culture, we just, we don't know how to do that.
We haven't, we haven't retained that skill that God created in us. We've lost sight of this ability
to just say, it's enough. I have enough. I've done enough. This is the invitation we have from God.
The second thing I want us to see is that throughout this whole first chapter of Genesis,
is actually rhythmic Hebrew poetry. And every day of creation ends with the same words. There was evening
and there was morning. Again, this is part of God weaving into creation, the Sabbath rhythm. The
biblical day doesn't start when we wake up. It starts when we go to bed. The biblical day starts
with the evening of rest. It's this reminder, this invitation that we don't have to work to accomplish
to strive for God's love, that it's actually a gift that's been given to us, that our day starts with
us going to sleep. And not only that, not only does we see this evening and morning starting, but you'll
notice that I said that it's this repeated phrase that happens after every day. The only challenge to that
is that it actually doesn't, we don't get that phrase on the seventh day. We don't get there's evening and
morning on the seventh day. It's almost as if the author of this creation account wants us to realize
that the seventh day of rest is this ongoing invitation that never ends. He's emphasizing this
rhythm of God's good creation in Eden that will produce this experience of ongoing rest that's woven into
the fabric of creation, built into our design as image bearers of God. This is a pattern we see in Genesis
of work and rest. From the first page of Scripture, God is communicating to his children that they are
loved and valued before they produce anything. Their day starts with rest, their week starts with rest.
And I just, for a moment, I just want us to take a deep breath and receive that.
Because most of us, depending on what you do for a job or what your parents were like or where you
went to school, you have this low grade hum of anxiety about trying to prove your worth to those around
you. And the one who created you and made you is saying to you this morning, you don't have to do
anything to prove your worth or your value to me. You are valuable to me because I made you in my image.
From the first pages of the Scriptures, God is teaching us this. And I think if you're in here
and you're a parent, you've probably had this experience of getting home late from work or an
event or an activity, your children are already in bed. And have you ever just stumbled into your
children's room and just watched them sleep? Something so wonderful about just watching my baby
sleep and just love, there's not, I can't love him any more than I love him in that moment.
And he's doing nothing but breathing. He's staying alive, which is great. I'm thankful that he does that.
But he's not adding any value to my life. He's not producing anything for me. He's just resting
in safety as my child. And this is the way that God wants us to see that he feels about us from the
first pages of Scripture. Not only do we see that Sabbath is throughout every day, evening and morning,
the day starts with rest. Not only is it at the climax of the creation story where the seventh day
of rest is kind of never ending, it's just left hanging there. But some commentators would actually
point out that there's a chiastic structure to the first creation account. And we're going to get
technical here for just a second. Can you stay with me? Chiastic structure is this way that Hebrew
poetry is structured, that kind of the beginning builds toward the middle and then it builds out
from the middle towards the end. And what oftentimes the author wants you to do is focus in on the very
center of the poem. And so if we take this structure of Genesis and we look at the very
center of the poem, we would come to day four of creation. In Genesis chapter one, verse 14, it says,
and God said, let there be lights in the vault of the sky to separate the day from the night. Let them
serve as signs to mark sacred times and days and years, and let them be lights in the vault of the sky
to give light on the earth. And it was so. God made two great lights, the greater light to govern the day,
the lesser night to govern the night. He also made the stars. God set them in the vault of the sky to
give light on the earth, to govern the day and the night, and to separate light from darkness. And God saw
that it was good. It was evening and morning on the fourth day. Now what's interesting, if you give any
credence to this idea that this might be a chiastic structures, the center word of the center verse is
this word, this Hebrew word, moed. I think we have it on the screen. And depending on what your translation
says, the NIV says sacred times. What's interesting is that this word is actually used later in the Old
Testament to talk about Sabbath. It's this appointed time that God has made for his people to stop and to
meet with him. So not only is Sabbath found from day to day in the Genesis account, not only is it
climaxed at the end, but if you take this point that it is actually built into the center of the poem,
it's this invitation to see that Sabbath is all throughout creation. This balance of work and rest is
actually in the fabric of God's creation. Leviticus chapter 23 talks about these appointed times.
It's literally the word moed. It's the same author of Genesis writing Leviticus. And God is saying,
there are appointed times that I have set for you to stop, to rest, to worship, and to delight. He starts
that list off with the weekly Sabbath. You're invited to stop producing, to rest, to enjoy God's creation.
He goes on after the weekly Sabbath and gives six other annual festivals. So with the weekly Sabbath
and the six annual festivals, there's a pattern of seven there. And then every seven years, there's a
Sabbath year. Every seven years, there's the year of Jubilee. It's this rhythm of creation that God is
inviting his people to participate in creation. Productivity, efficiency, all of these things are
not bad things. These are part of our image-bearing nature, but it's this balance of work and rest. And
it's built on this pattern of seven all throughout the Scriptures. What's interesting to me when you
think about that is actually this seven-day week has no real scientific reasoning.
Our month is built on the moon. Our year is built on the sun. Our week is built on, ask scientists,
and they will say, it's just been like that for a long time, and it seems to work, so we don't mess
with it. And I would say, woven into the fabric of creation. There's actually been attempts to change
this in the past, and they have not gone well. So we keep coming back to this rhythm of creation
that God has invited us into. Another really interesting fact, if you're into scientifically proving
what the Bible says, there was a recent study done on a group of Christians that really takes seriously
the pattern of Sabbath. They would kind of adhere to it legalistically. And a scientist did this study
on them and found that they, as a group, had an 11-year longer lifespan on average. Like, they lived
longer because they received the invitation of God to work in the pattern of creation, to stop producing
into rest, to stop doing more than they needed to do, and to enjoy God's creation. So my first argument this
morning is that Sabbath isn't an outdated religious command, but it is a rhythm of rest woven into the
created order. And all of this points to the reality that we are not machines created for productivity, but we
are image bearers of the creator who is inviting us to order his life, order our life, our
around his appointed times and seasons and structures. We're invited to have a rhythm of work
and pleasure and rest. And I hope that that encourages you this morning. I'm not trying to lay on some
burden from you. I'm trying to just give you an idea that maybe God is inviting you into something that
you didn't know you were being invited into. And maybe the reason that we're tired and worn out is
because we've actually been living counterculturally from God's ordained rhythm. Maybe we're trying to
swim upstream so hard and so fast, and that's why we're exhausted. So Sabbath is woven into the rhythm
of creation. It's also a counter-formational invitation to God's people. Later in Exodus chapter 20,
we read these words starting in verse 8. Moses says to the people, actually God through Moses says to the
people of Israel, remember the Sabbath day by keeping it holy. Six days you shall labor and do all your
work, but the seventh day is a Sabbath, a stop to the Lord your God. On it you shall not do any work,
neither you, nor your son, nor your daughter, nor your male or female servant, nor your animals,
nor your foreigners residing in the towns. For in six days, the Lord made the heavens and the earth
and the sea and all that is in them, but he rested on the seventh day. Therefore, the Lord blessed the
Sabbath day and made it holy. So a few things I want to point out here from this passage. The first is
that it is a part of the 10 commandments. Does that surprise anybody? Did anybody not know that?
See, I think there's this thing that we like to do as Protestant Christians, as Anabaptist
Christians. We like to look at the Old Testament law and say that no longer applies to New Testament
Christians, but pretty much every Christian that I've ever heard say the Old Testament law doesn't
apply to me. I'll say, what about the 10 commandments? And they all say, yeah, that's pretty good. We
should do that. Right? Most people would argue that. We'd say, yeah, the 10 commandments, that's like the
core. That's the central thing. Those are the things that we should do. And yet we find that in the 10
commandments, actually, if you do a word count of the 10 commandments, 37% of the 10 commandments is
about the Sabbath. So American New Testament Christians who would say, we don't need to do the
Old Testament law, but yeah, let's stick with the 10 commandments. I would say that most of us actually
brag about breaking 37% of the 10 commandments. We brag about how busy we are, about how much we're doing,
about how all the things that we have going on. We wouldn't do that about lying or stealing or
murdering, but we do do that about not resting. It's part of the 10 commandments. Not only that,
it doesn't seem to be a new command. It's not like it just came to the Israelites. It doesn't say,
here's a new command. It says, remember. Remember this thing that's been woven into creation from the
beginning of time. Remember when we just told you about Genesis and God's creation and God's appointed
times. Remember these things. And thirdly, it's given to a people who have just been brought out
of slavery for 400 years. And so what I think God is doing to them when he's saying remember is he's
telling them, listen, I know you haven't been able to do this thing for 400 years. You have been enslaved to
the Egyptians. They have not let you take a moment to rest. And I want to invite you to remember this
pattern of rest that I have given you from the beginning of creation. You are not what you produce.
You are an image bearer of God. It is a command that is given to form them out of their identity as
slaves and back into their identity as image bearers and children of God, the God who rests.
And if we think about the cultural imagination of an enslaved people group,
their whole identity, their whole, everything they would have just conceived about value and worth would
have been about productivity and efficiency. They would have found their value in what they produced.
They'd have this internal Pharaoh. Every time they were invited to rest, they'd hear Pharaoh saying,
if you don't work, you don't eat. Every time they try to obey the command of God,
they'd hear this internal Pharaoh saying that if you don't add value to the community, that you're not
worth anything. And I think in the cultural place that we exist, we often also have this internal Pharaoh
that tells us that we can't rest, that we don't deserve rest, that there's too much to be done,
that there's too much to be fixed. And God through Moses is intentionally reminding
us and the people of Israel about the rhythm of creation, hoping to deform their secular view of
value and reclaim the sacred view that we are valuable because who God made us to be. It's a
counter-formational command. So whether you think Sabbath is a binding command for New Testament
believers or not, this command to the Israelites seems like a much needed counter-formational invitation
to us. So I'm not here to argue that you have to do it. I'm actually just here exposing to you an
invitation that I think has been in the Scriptures all along, but we've ignored. And many of us,
it's not our fault. Like this is just how we've been taught the Scriptures. But I think this is an
invitation that we should consider. It's a counter-formational one. As we live in this fast-paced,
individualistic consumer culture, we need a regular reminder that our value is not in what we produce
or what we can consume, but by the God who made us, loved us, and modeled for us rest as an act of
counter-cultural worship to him. I love how Walter Brueggemann puts it. He says,
Sabbath is not simply a pause. It is an act of resistance against the rhythm of the world.
And so it's this invitation to order our lives differently. Does that sound like following Jesus?
This is what the New Testament is. This is when Jesus says, my yoke is easy, my burden is light. He's
inviting them to build their life on a new rhythm, a new pattern. And this pattern is actually resistance
to the pattern of the world. So I want to get practical before I try to land this uncomfortable plane.
You might be asking yourself, am I saying Christians should imitate Jewish practices and have strict rules
around what they can and cannot do from sundown Friday to sundown Saturday?
No, no. Dodged a bullet there, right? Am I saying a weekly 24-hour period of time to stop working
and to rest is a binding command for new Christians? Not necessarily. You don't get a no there because
there are many scholars and theologians that would argue that it's the case, but it's totally debatable.
And I'm not going to put that burden on you, but I would say that I think God is inviting us to consider
how we might build an intentional moed, an appointed time, weekly, where we stop working, we rest, we delight in his creation, and we worship him.
It brings internal, deep rest to our souls that we were made for.
It's an invitation that is easier for some of us to receive than others.
And so if you're in here and you're like, this just seems impossible to me, I would encourage you to start thinking about a smaller chunk of time.
Think about four hours where you do no chores, where you do nothing that needs to get done,
where you stop working and you just do things that you enjoy.
You have time with family, you read a book, you get outside, you have a good meal with family and friends.
You take a nap.
Married couples, you take a nap.
If you read the rabbis, the rabbis are very strict about our Jewish brothers and sisters who are married taking naps on the Sabbath.
I'm just telling you.
This is an invitation from God.
Wrap it up, brother, somebody says.
I love that.
I said it was an uncomfortable plane.
All right.
So for some of this, this is very far off reality that we'd have to really look at our calendars over the next year to strategically think about how we might receive this invitation.
Think about your calendars, your commitments.
What good things might you need to begin to say no to so that you can say yes to something better?
What if this fear of missing out?
We're saying yes to all of these good things.
And because we're saying yes to all of these good things, we have no time to say yes to the thing that we need most.
And what help might you require to have on a regular, to have a regular period of rest?
It's funny.
I thought I had my iPad on Do Not Disturb.
I just have, I just got a text from a friend who's got a three-year-old and twins.
And he's like, hey, can you watch my kids?
Right?
And really, when we talk about doing life in community, doing life in small groups, like, I want this conversation to happen because there are some of you that literally, without the help of somebody else, you could not have a true Sabbath.
And some of us have, we're in stages of life and periods of life where we can Sabbath more than 24 hours, and we could give some of our time back to share with others so that we could all experience this rhythm of rest in our lives.
That text came at the perfect time because that was the next point in my outline.
If we have more than enough time, how can we support others to experience this?
For the past while now, in week three of this series, we're actually going to hear from my friend Brian.
Him and his family have been practicing this pretty intentionally for a long time, and they've invited my family to a Shabbat dinner every Saturday night.
And this is an awesome opportunity for us.
We've kind of set it aside on our calendar as much, as often as it works.
We don't do it every week.
They don't do it every week at their house.
And so it's just like as much as we can do it.
And Brian's not a pastor, so I would say Sunday's not a work day for you.
So you guys do sundown Saturday to sundown Sunday.
I love you guys.
I love doing this.
It feels like work.
So my Sabbath is kind of like sundown Friday to sundown Saturday.
So it's this awesome kind of coming together where I'm kind of celebrating the end of my restful day,
and they're kind of like just kicking it off.
And it's this opportunity for us to enjoy each other's company, to have good meals and good conversation,
and just to remind ourselves that God loves us, that our day starts with rest, that our week starts with rest,
that our value is found not in what we can produce, but in who God made us to be.
A.J. Swoboda says it this way, Sabbath is permission to have one day a week where we're not trying to fix the world.
We're allowing God to fix us.
And if we don't have that, does this not sound like our life?
We will move from crisis to crisis and just make things worse.
Sabbath is an invitation, a counter-cultural one, to not try and fix something for a day.
Just let God fix us.
All right.
As we land the uncomfortable plane, point number three, Sabbath is a foretaste of new creation.
Revelation chapter 21.
So we saw in the Genesis account of God's good created order that the sun and the moon was given to show us God's appointed time for Sabbath rest.
Literally, the central day in the creation story is day four, where God gives us the sun and the moon,
and he says he gives it to us, yes, for years and for months, but also for appointed times,
for sacred times to experience rest and worship and communion with the Father.
The sun and the moon are given to show us appointed times of Sabbath rest.
And we pick up in Revelation chapter 21 and read verse 23.
I'll start in 22.
I did not see a temple in the city because the Lord, the God Almighty, and the Lamb are its temple.
This is after Christ's second coming.
This is the fulfillment of all things.
This is new Eden.
This is new Jerusalem.
This is everlasting peace.
And it says in verse 23, the city does not need the sun or the moon to shine on it,
for the glory of God gives it light, and the Lamb is its lamp.
So, the very first pages of Scripture were given the sun and the moon for the sake of showing us the appointed times to stop and delight and rest and worship God.
And in Revelation, it says, we won't need the sun and the moon to do that for us anymore because all of creation will be an experience of everlasting rest and worship in the Father.
Our value will not be in what we produce, but in who we are.
Because all of eternity will be a moed, an appointed time of connection with God through Christ.
And for those of us that are followers of Jesus, I would say this is a reality that began in part when Christ was raised.
Think about the schedule of Holy Week.
Christ crucified on Friday.
His body lay rest on the Sabbath day.
And on Sunday morning, he rose again on the eighth day, or you might say the first day of the next week,
almost symbolically indicating that a new rhythm of new creation is available through the resurrection of Jesus.
That there's this new way of being, this new way of existing with God that we've been invited to because Christ conquered sin, death, and the grave.
It's available here and now for those of us who trust in Christ.
It's an invitation to live into the freedom and rest that is ours in Christ now while we await its ultimate fulfillment.
I love how Dr. N.T. Wright puts it.
The point of Sabbath is not simply to stop working, but to learn how to live as God's people in God's world.
I think we see it on the first pages of Scripture.
We see it developed throughout the Bible, and we see it fulfilled on the last page of Scripture.
And we live in this in-between time now as believers, where the freedom and victory has been won by Jesus,
but we're still waiting the ultimate fulfillment.
And so now we are invited to begin to pattern our lives on the pattern that God created us for.
It's an opportunity for us to live now as God's people in God's world before He returns.
So the question I want to leave us with this week is,
what if our packed schedules, our lack of downtime, our full credit cards that are a result of FOMA
are actually causing us to miss out on the thing we need most?
Rest for our anxious souls.
What if we're so busy following the scheduling patterns of this world around us that we're actually missing an opportunity to show the world a better way to live?
If we're, as Christians, supposed to be a countercultural witness, a city on a hill, salt in the earth,
why is it that we are just as anxious as our neighbors and our coworkers and our friends?
Why is it that we are just as tired and worn out?
Is it possibly because we actually haven't been receiving an invitation to take on the yoke of Jesus that is light,
that leads to rest for our souls?
Might we be missing out on a witness to our neighbors to say that you are not what you consume,
you are not what you produce, but you are actually a child of the Most High God.
And what might God do in you and through you if you accepted this invitation
and work towards giving Him a weekly appointed time to stop producing, to rest,
to delight in His creation and to worship Him?
This is the invitation that we're gonna be considering over the next four weeks.
And I don't expect all of you to buy in.
I don't even expect 50% of you to buy in.
I'm happy to receive emails with pushback,
but I just, from the outset, want to point out that I think it's a rhythm that we see throughout all of Scripture.
It's a thread.
This appointed time to stop, to rest.
I'd love to invite all of you to stand as we conclude.
And I just want to pray this invitation of Jesus over all of us.
Matthew 11,
Then Jesus said,
Come to me, all of you who are weary,
and carry heavy burdens,
and I will give you rest.
Take my yoke upon you.
Let me teach you because I am humble and gentle at heart,
and you will find rest for your souls.
For my yoke is easy to bear,
and the burden I give you is light.
Father,
for each person in this room that's feeling worn out,
tired,
anxious,
God, I don't know,
I don't know what part Sabbath might play in this invitation,
but I pray that they would experience you as one who has a light yoke,
an easy burden.
God, that they would receive rest for their souls
because they are not what they produce or what they consume,
but they are a child of the Most High God.
God, for those of us that have more than enough time on our hands,
may we see that as an asset to come alongside our brothers and sisters in Christ
to help them experience this rest.
And God, may this church be a people
who are day by day learning how to live as God's people in God's world
as we await your ultimate return.
In Jesus' name I pray.
Amen.
All right, church,
there should be some people at the prayer tent if you need prayer.
Other than that,
you are dismissed.
Amen.
Thank you.